David M. Padilla

Full Stack Web Developer

Over 5+ years of experience establishing personal relationships through communications as well as strong analytical skills for interpreting documentation and data to resolve conflicts. Successful in working both team and self-directed settings. Up-and-coming Full Stack Web Developer eager to make an impact in designing and maintaining the complexities of your applications.

Experience

2017-08 - Financial Associate I - Health & Welfare

2018-09

Fidelity Investments

- Analyzed thousands of IBM employee records to uncover hidden solutions unseen by more experienced associates.
- Downgraded critical setbacks into minor hiccups through positive verbiage, empathy, and ownership.
- Recognized by VP of Participant Services to take on more managerial duties such as peer mentorship and procedural write-ups.

2014-01 - Scheduling Agent

2017-07

AIG VALIC

- Reestablished communication between advisors and their clients, which in turn resulted in increases to their monthly contributions as well as greater client retention.
- Helped one advisor significantly add over a quarter million in assets from multiple discovery meetings, which was then managed through the company.
- Created new departmental procedures and statistics through Excel to increase performance from both the scheduling staff and supervisor.

Education

2018-10 -

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

2019-04 Coding Boot Camp - Full Stack Web Development Certification

An intensive 24 week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications.

Project Highlights

CineGrub is a front-end application that seamlessly integrates the ability to find movies and restaurants nearby via zip code. Users can also save any movie or restaurant result found and send invitations to friends.

https://cinegrub.com/

jQuery, RESTful APIs, Firebase

Recipedia is a MERN-stack application that makes weekly meal planning easier. Designed with the busy professional in mind, the site allows users to search for recipes, favorite them for future reference, and build a weekly menu.

https://my-recipedia.com/
Material-UI, React, MongoDB

Schedulr is a full stack application that any client can use to schedule or manage appointments for customers. In addition, clients may also send friendly text reminders to their customer's mobile number.

https://app-schedulr.herokuapp.com/

Bootstrap 4, Handlebars, MySQL

Personal Info

Address

Raleigh, NC 27615

Phone

+1 919 869 9647

Email

davidpadilla.dev@gmail.com

Website

davidpadilla.io

GitHub

github.com/dpadillajs

Technical Skills

HTML5

CSS3

Bootstrap 4

Material-UI

JavaScript

jQuery

JSON

Handlebars

ECMAScript 2015

React

Node.js

Express

Firebase

NoSQL

MySQL

Sequelize

MongoDB

Mongoose

Chrome DevTools

RESTful APIs